Even in war… murder is murder.
Casualties of War is a drama, history, war film directed by Brian De Palma.
During the Vietnam War, a soldier finds himself the outsider of his own
squad when they unnecessarily kidnap a female villager.
Private Eriksson, played by Michael J. Fox.
Sgt. Tony Meserve, played by Sean Penn.
Cpl. Thomas E. Clark, played by Don Harvey.
Private Herbert Hatcher, played by John C. Reilly.
Private Antonio Diaz, played by John Leguizamo.
Oanh, played by Thuy Thu Le.
Casualties of War is a 1989 American war drama film directed by Brian De Palma and written by David Rabe, based
primarily on an article written by Daniel Lang for The New Yorker in 1969, which was later published as a book.
The film stars Michael J.
Fox and Sean Penn and is based on the events of the 1966 incident on Hill 192 during the Vietnam War, in which a
Vietnamese woman was kidnapped from her village, raped, and murdered by a squad of American soldiers.
All names and some details of the true story were altered for the film.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietcong, rape, court, menace.
The tone is emotional.